SUBHAJIT DAS

8961219163 | subhajit.das@iiitb.net | Kolkata

PROFILE SUMMARY

Wiley Certified Data Scientist (CZN-CDS-KOL-280119002) with an over four years of experience in analysis, design, development of predictive analytical models with an expertise in R, Python and SQL. Deep understanding of technology with a demonstrated ability to deliver valuable insights via analytics and advanced machine learning algorithms.

ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

Master of Science - MS, Data Science | CGPA 3.63/4 | Year- 2020
 Liverpool John Moores University, UK

Post Graduate Diploma, Data Science I CGPA 3.52/4

IIIT, Bangalore

Year- 2018

B. Tech, Electronics and Communication Engineering I CGPA 7.78/10

Year- 2014

Kalyani Government Engineering College | West Bengal University of Technology, Kolkata

WORK EXPERIENCE

Current Organization: *Cognizant*, Associate Data Scientist, Kolkata June 2018 – Present

- Analysed the Hospital Care Professional (HCP) behaviours through Key Driving Factors (linear regression) with respect to
 actual sales of a drug. Increased growth on selling drug revenue by leveraging HCP's acquisitions and improved physician
 marketing strategies through Segmenting them according to their drug Prescribing pattern using K-Means clustering
 algorithm and Developed a propensity score using advanced machine learning algorithm (Logistic Regression, XGBoost) for
 each HCP's which will devise a successful go to market strategy and to maximize ROI of each SFE rep's call.
- SAS to R migration of different protocols like 'Logit-Log' is a calculation method for quantification of antigenic mass by Elisa, based on logit log transformation and linear regression and Visualize those using R Shiny.
- Underlying reasons behind patient absenteeism to visit HCP or clinic and **strategize** to improve the conversions rate. It is analysed through 'Compellon Causality Engine' (Hackathon Winner).

Previous Organization: *Jardine Lloyd Thomson*, Analytics Consultant, Mumbai July 2017 - May 2018

- Developed and implemented a marketing strategy to optimize the marketing cost and achieve 80% of total responders at
 the minimum possible cost for the selling of an Investment product for a UK based multinational bank and target the one's,
 most likely to respond in the next telemarketing campaign using advanced analytical predictive models.
- Developed an attrition analytics framework that uses a predictive model to generate a score for each employee of leaving the organization using Logistic Regression & Random Forest and came up with top 3 reasons for Employee attrition to design an Early Warning System framework.
- Built a model using **Support Vector Machine** to identify the **handwritten digits** between 0 to 9 written in an image. (POC)

Previous Organization: *Accenture*, Application Development Analyst, Mumbai April 2015 - July 2017

- **Forecasted the sales and the demand** of an online store for its top two most profitable and consistent segment for the next six months, using **auto ARIMA** and **consulted** the strategy to manage the revenue and inventory accordingly.
- Evaluate a predictive model to identify the customers who are at the risk of cancelling their membership of a premium club boasts a large customer base, developed using supervised classification machine learning algorithms.
- Build the **portfolio of risk assessment** with an **exploratory data analysis** to find the key driving factors behind loan default and analysed the correlation between different variables using **Heatmap** and created dashboard using **Tableau**.

KEY SKILLS

- Machine Learning Modelling Techniques
- Visualization: Seaborn, Ggplot2, Tableau, RShiny
- Statistics & Hypothesis Testing
- Analytics Languages: R, Python, SQL, SparkR, PySpark
- Databases: SQL Server 2008, MySQL
- DevOps- Jenkins, AWS, GitHub, Amazon S3, EMR Cluster

ACCOLADES

• School level success in All India Mathematics Olympiad, National Talent Search Competition, National Science Olympiad.